Guide to the William R. George family papers, 1750-1989.
George, William R. family papers, 1750-1989.
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Omessa, Henri, Feb. - Mar.1915 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Letter from William R. George to his parents; Letters from citizens.
  - Mitchell, Guy C.; Babcock, Lester F., Mar. 1915 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Platt, H.L.; Brooks, Paul B.; Omessa, Henri, Apr. 1915 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Prison Association of New York; "Corporation Charter of Pioneer City."
  - Schurman, Jacob Gould; LeRoy, Betty; Smith, Jacob G., May - Jun.1915 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Schurman, Jacob Gould; Lindsay, John D.; Smith, Jacob G.; Omessa, Henri, Jun. - Jul.1915 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    New York Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children.
  - George, Mary B.; Omessa, Henri, Aug.Sep1915 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Omessa, Henri, Jan. - Sep.1915 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Letter to Charles F. Pekor from William R. George concerning government at George Junior Republic; Committee on Charities of the Constitutional Convention.
  - McReynolds, Merle, Oct. 1915 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    List of housemothers. (Annotations)
  - (Box 17)
  - White, Andrew Dickson; Albertson, Henry H., Nov. 1915 (Folder 10)
  - Farm census, Nov1915 (Folder 11)
  - Omessa, Henri; Forbes, Alexander, Dec. 1915 (Folder 12)
  - Shanley, Mildred E., Dec. 1915 (Folder 13)
  - LeRoy, Betty, 1915 (Folder 14)
    "Social Hospital"; Excerpts from William R. George's diary.
  - Omessa, Henri, Oct. - Dec.1915 (Folder 15)
  - Burlington County Farm Census, 1915 (Folder 16-24)
  - Maps and layouts, 1915 (Folder 25)
  - Robinson, Prescott W.; Omessa, Henri, Jan. 1916 (Folder 26)
    Letters from citizens; Excerpts from William R. George's diary.
  - Hobson, Frances Thayer; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jan. 1916 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Schell, R. Montgomery; Welton, Tom; Omessa, Henri, Feb. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Robinson, Prescott W.; Koch, Henry J., Feb. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Perry; Schell, R. Montgomery; Koch, Henry J.; Hurley, John W., Feb. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Garimaldi, Edward; Koch, Henry J.; Hurley, John W., Feb. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Bannon, Mamie; Koch, Henry J.; McReynolds, Merle, Feb. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Unsworth, Mary E.; Koch, Henry J., Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Bernstein, Ludwig B., Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Powell, Wilson M., Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Corbett, R.M.; Erwin, Marion, Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Stone, John L.; Taylor, Mildred, Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Application blank for a boy to George Junior Republic.
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Gute, William A., Mar. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Gute, William A., Ap.1916 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Hurley, Nellie; Omessa, Henri., Ap.1916 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Erwin, Marion; Angier, Roswell P.; Davis, Paul A., Apr. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Erwin, Marion, Ap.1916 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Erwin, Marion; Shoemaker, Elizabeth T., Apr. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    "Nothing Without Labor."
  - Mundell, J.A.; Erwin, Marion; Dapping, William O., May 1916 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Proposed George Junior Republic in Ontario, Canada.
  - Schell, R. Montgomery; Fenigstonn, B. Phyllis; Erwin, Marion, May 1916 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Erwin, Marion; Offer, George E.; Thurston, Henry W., May 1916 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Miller Corset Company; National Junior Republic.
  - Cohen, Selma N., May1916 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Shoemaker, Elizabeth T.; Offer, George E.; Mundell, J.A.; Gute, William A., May 1916 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    National Junior Republic; Letters from citizens; William R. George's answers to a questionnaire concerning self government and other matters.
  - Gute, William A.; Offer, George E., Jun. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Gute, William A.; Fowler, Kate; McCord, Edith, Jun. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Miller, Gerrit Smith; Snyder, George, Jun. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Letters to ex-citizens.
  - Whetzel, H.H.; Snyder, George, Jul1916 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Omessa, Henri; Smith, Charles Orchard, Jul. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    Anonymous letter describing the character and accomplishments of William R. George.
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jul. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Dawson, Charles B., Ja.1916 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Dapping, William O., FebJul.1916 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Charles Orchard, Au.1916 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Au.1916 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Aug. 1916 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Smith, Charles Orchard; Marshall, Bob; LeRoy, Harris G.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Stoddart, Bessie D., Sept. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Letter from a citizen wanting to go home.
  - Schneider, Henry C., Sept. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    George Junior Republic Parent or Guardian's Surrender form.
  - Schneider, Henry C., Oct. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    George Junior Republic cash statement.
  - Schneider, Henry C.; Streeter, H. Adele, Oct. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Streeter, H. Adele; Schneider, Henry C., Oct. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Schneider, Henry C.; McReynolds, Merle; Streeter, H. Adele, Oct. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Wright, Henry C., Aug. - Sep.1916 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Schneider, Henry C., Sept. - Oct.1916 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Schell, R. Montgomery; Streeter, H. Adele, Nov. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - MacLeod, Josephine; Stoddard, Ralph G.; Schneider, Henry C.; Willet, Ellis, Nov. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Schell, R. Montgomery; Stoddard, Ralph G.; Schneider, Henry C., Nov. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mateer, Ada Haven; Hurley, John W.; Schneider, Henry C., Dec. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Schneider, Henry C.; Streeter, H. Adele, Dec. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Levin, Leonard S.; Schneider, Henry C., Dec. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Albertson, Henry H., Dec. 1916 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Brewster, Betty; Gute, William A., 1916 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    "The Social Sanitarium"; Draft of a speech by William R. George. (Annotations.)
  - Rumball, Catherine; Dewey, John; LeRoy, Harris G., 1916 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    "The Junior Republic" dictation by William R. George; "Founder's Day" by W. Leo Johnson.
  - Schell, Alice M., 1916 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    "Practical Working of the Social Sanitarium in the George Junior Republic"; "The Junior Municipality"; "Relative to the Inter-relation of Concerns not Directly Concerned with the Junior Republic but Employing its Citizens, and the Junior Republic Government, and the Junior Republic Association."
  - "Constitution of Junior Republic"; Bulletins 1 - 6., 1916 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Bulletins 7 - 18., 1916 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Schneider, Henry C., Aug. - Dec.1916 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report; "School Children as Census Takers.", 1916 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Unsworth, Mary E.; St. John, Arthur J., Jan. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Thomas, Arthur P., Ja.1917 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Norton, Gertrude; Levin, Leonard S., Jan. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Lane, Winthrop D.; Gute, William A., Jan. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Hobson, Frances Thayer; Levin, Leonard S.; Lane, Winthrop D., Jan. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Boys' Brotherhood Republic.
  - Gute, William A.; Schneider, Henry C., Feb. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Thomas, Arthur P.; Schneider, Henry C.; Peck, Allen D.; Levin, Leonard S., Feb. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - McReynolds, Merle; Frost, E. Doreen; Schneider, Henry C., Feb. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Frost, E. Doreen, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Schneider, Henry C.; Childs, William A., Mar. 1917 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Gordon, S. Moore; Rockefeller, John D. Jr., Feb. - Mar.1917 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    Prospective George Junior Republic in China.
  - Lane, Winthrop D.; Bell, Willard; Oswald, John Clyde, Apr. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Omessa, Henri; Gute, William A.; Hotchkiss, Willard E., Apr. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Rexford, Frank A.; Schneider, Henry, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Lane, Winthrop D.; Childs, William A., Apr. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    "School Children as Census Takers."
  - LaMarche, George; Rexford, Frank A.; Smith, Jacob G.; Chandler, Ethel, Apr. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Ida; Mateer, Ada Haven; Cadoo, Charles; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, May 1917 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Gaither, Nina Williams; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Oswald, John Clyde, May 1917 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Schneider, Henry C.; Hoover, Herbert; Gute, William A., Jun. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Offer, George E.; Peck, Allen D.; Omessa, Henri, Jun. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - LeRoy, Harris G., Jun. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Lane, Winthrop D.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, May 1917 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - St. John, Arthur J.; Gute, William A.; Gaither, Nina Williams; Hoover, Herbert, May - Jun.1917 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Gute, William A.; Thomas, Arthur P., Jul. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Gute, William A.; Howland, Emily, Jul. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Bell, Ida, Au.1917 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Bell, James M., Au.1917 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Gute, William A.; Howland, Emily; Bell, Ida; Oswald, John Clyde, Jul. - Aug.1917 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Corona Typewriter Company.
  - Greene, Jerome D., Sept. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Lyle, Chester A.; Johnson, W. Leo; Streeter, H. Adele, Sept. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Shanley, Mildred E.; Schneider, Leah F., Oct. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Schneider, Leah F.; Streeter, H. Adele, Oct. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - "Prison Walls Without a Prison -- A Plan for Restraining and Reforming Offenders in Farm Villages.", Nov. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Townsend, R.D.; Forbes, Alexander, No.1917 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Letters from citizens, De.1917 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Gute, William A., Dec. 1917 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Draft of annual report by William R. George, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Schneider, Leah F., Sept. - Oct.1917 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Shanley, Mildred E.; Schneider, Leah F., Oct. - Dec.1917 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    "Social Sanitarium" by William R. George; Draft of Annual Report.
  - Gute, William A.; Schneider, Henry C.; Gute, Mary R., Jan. 1918 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Weeker, John M., Jan. 1918 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Garimaldi, Edward; Baldwin, Dorothy; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jan. 1918 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Curtis, Henry H.; LaMarche, George, Feb. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Schneider, Henry C.; Ganyard, Mervin B.; Albertson, Henry H.; Osler, Rebecca T.; Thomas, Arthur P.; Parker, Esther E. (Annotations.), Feb. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Stoddart, Bessie D.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; LaMarche, George, Jan.Feb1918 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Curtis, Henry H.; Ganyard, Mervin B.; Schneider, Henry C., Mar. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Garimaldi, Edward; Wright, Florence M. (Annotations.), Mar. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Cadoo, Charles; Robbins, Jack; Garimaldi, Edward, Apr. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Ganyard, Mervin B.; Schneider, Henry C., Apr. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Garimaldi, Edward; Schneider, Henry C., May 1918 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Ganyard, Mervin B.; Beach, William G., May 1918 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, W. Leo; Schneider, Henry C.; Garimaldi, Edward; Osler, Rebecca T.; Smith, Jacob G.; Levin, Leonard S., Jun. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Schneider, Henry C., Jul. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Perry, Edward W., Aug. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Garimaldi, Edward; O'Connor, Timothy J.; Schneider, Henry C., Sept. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Dapping, William O.; Schneider, Henry C.; LaMarche, George; Stoddart, Bessie D.; McReynolds, Merle, Oct. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Atlantic Woolen Mills.
  - McAllister, Peter F.; Platt, H.L.; Ganyard, Mervin B., Nov. - Dec.1918 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - "The Delinquent Child and Education"; "Concerning the Admittance of Citizens to the George Junior Republic"; Patriotic pledge of girl citizens, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Shoemaker, Elizabeth T., 1918 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    "Concerning Discipline"; Draft of article by William R. George concerning early social work.
  - "The Junior Republic.", 1918 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Thomas, Arthur P., 1918 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    Annual Report for the George Junior Republic; Draft of article concerning George Junior Republic boys in war; List of George Junior Republic boys in the war.
  - Beach, William G.; Gute, William A.; Welling, Richard, Jan. 1919 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Parker, John A.; LaMarche, George; White, Andrew Dickson, Jan. 1919 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    Agreements with Miss Freeman.
  - Dapping, William O.; Marshall, Beulah Greenway, Feb. - Mar.1919 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    Letter from William R. George to Esther George.
  - LaMarche, George; Boynton, Frank David; Schneider, Henry C.; Johnson, W. Leo, Apr. - May1919 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Boynton, Frank David; Ganyard, Mervin B., May - Jun.1919 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - "Practical Working of the Social Sanitarium.", Jul. 1919 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Jacob G.; Boynton, Frank David, Aug. - Sep.1919 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    Notes from William R. George to William A. Gute concerning the operation of a Junior Republic.
  - Selden, Maud G.; Stanton, Vera M., Oct. - Dec.1919 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - "The Junior Republic Idea"; Notes about the "four principles" of a Junior Republic. (Annotations.), 1919 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - "Tim" (the story of Timothy O'Connor, by William R. George)., 1919 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - "Tim" (the story of Timothy O'Connor by William R. George)., 1919 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - "The Social Doctor"; "The Spiritual.", 1919 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Bills, Charles B.; Oswald, John Clyde; Kirkland, J.B.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jan. - May 1920 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    George Junior Republic Alumni News, list of ex-citizens.
  - Richardson, C. Spencer; Dapping, William O., Jun. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Dapping, William O.; St. John, Arthur J.; Schell, R. Montgomery, Jul. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    List of ex-citizens; Letter to the Council for Democratic Training.
  - Miller, C. Spencer, Aug. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    "The Social Sanitarium"; "Junior Citizens League." (Annotations.)
  - Miller, C. Spencer; Snyder, George, Sept. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Information about boys and girls at George Junior Republic.
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Sinclair, Edmund, Oct. - Nov.1920 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    National Council for Democratic Training.
  - Sinclair, Edmund; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Phillips, Frank K., Dec. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Notes from a trip of William R. George; National Council for Democratic Training.
  - List of citizens from Ithaca, N.Y. (Annotations.), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "School News"; "Principles of the George Junior Republic" by William R. George; "What the Junior Republic Needs to Expand its Growth"; "Bulletin: For the Convenience and Guidance of Staff Members." (Annotations.), 1920 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Siebenlist, William A., ca. 1920 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - O'Connor, Timothy J.; Dapping, William O.; Oswald, John Clyde; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Feb. - Jun.1920 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Notes on ex-citizens. (Annotations.)
  - Dapping, William O.; Welling, Richard; Christiancy, George; Miller, C. Spencer; St. John, Arthur J., Jul. - Oct.1920 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Miller, C. Spencer; Oswald, John Clyde; Sinclair, Edmund, Nov. - Dec.1920 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "Junior Municipality.", 1920 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "The Social Doctor.", Jan. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Tatnall, Samuel W., 1921 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Bruner, Earle W., Feb. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    George Junior Republic of Western Pennsylvania; Letter from William R. George concerning the new year at George Junior Republic.
  - National Council for Democratic Training, Feb.1921 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Christiancy, George; Paddon, Mary E., Jan. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Miller, C. Spencer; Sinclair, Edmund; Tatnall, Samuel W., Feb. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Letters to Tatnall describing the values and principles of a Junior Republic.
  - Welling, Richard; Sinclair, Edmund; Oswald, John Clyde; Weeks, John M., Mar. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Dickens, M.F., 1921 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Letter to Trustees, Apr. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - George, Eleanor M., Apr. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Witmark, James, Mar. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Dickens, M.F., Apr. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    Requirements for admission to George Junior Republic.
  - Calder, John W., May 1921 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    Republic money.
  - Tatnall, Samuel W., 1921 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Manley, Barbara; Hagedorn, Herman. Dickens, M.F.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jun. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Calder, John W.; Tatnall, Samuel W.; LeRoy, Harris G., Jul. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Albertson, Henry H.; LeRoy, Harris G., Jul. 1921 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    List of salaries.
  - Calder, John; Tatnall, Samuel W., May - Jun.1921 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Jul. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Lee, Richard H., Aug. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Letter to Lee from William R. George concerning the operation of the George Junior Republic.
  - Hotchkiss, Willard E.; Lee, Richard H., Aug. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Tatnall, Samuel W., Sept. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Albertson, Henry H.; Smith, Jacob G.; Tatnall, Samuel W., Aug. - Sep.1921 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Hotchkiss, Willard E., Sept. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Woollcott, Alexander; Manley, Barbara; Lee, Richard H.; Welling, Richard. (Annotations.), Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Welling, Richard; Lee, Richard H.; Hurley, John W., Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Letter to Welling from William R. George concerning the "enemies" of the George Junior Republic.
  - Ganyard, Mervin B.; Hurley, Nellie, Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    "Concerning the Business Manager of the Republic"; "Concerning the Real Estate Adjoining the J. R. Property"; Minutes of the Trustees meeting.
  - Schell, R. Montgomery, Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Sinclair, Edmund; Woollcott, Alexander; LeRoy, Harris G., Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Jacob G., Oct. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - McAllister, Peter F.; Lee, Richard H., Nov. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Welling, Richard; Forbes, Waldo E.; Roberts, Harley F.; Forbes, Alexander; Smith, Jacob G.; Kirkland, J.B., Nov. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    George Junior Republic finances; Connecticut Junior Republic. (Annotations.)
  - Welling, Richard; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Forbes, Alexander; McAllister, Peter F., Nov. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    George Junior Republic finances; Forbes property.
  - Forbes, Alexander; Smith, Jacob G.; McAllister, Peter F., Nov. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    George Junior Republic National Fund.
  - Levin, Leonard S., Nov. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    Letter from Esther George describing the Georges' twenty fifth wedding anniversary and the state of the Republic.
  - Welling, Richard; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Bruner, Earle D.; McAllister, Peter F., Dec. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Large, Harold; Oswald, John Clyde; Welling, Richard; Miller, Hervey E., Dec. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - LeRoy, Betty; Leathers, Julia, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Smoking Law; Excerpted annotations; "The Junior Municipality"; "Concerning the Business Manager of the Republic."
  - Welling, Richard; Geller, Roscoe J.; Manley, Barbara; Mallory, Walter H.; Miller, Hervey E., Dec. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Dapping, William O., 1921 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    "The Junior Municipality"; Lists of names and addresses.
  - Livingston, Bessie; Welling, Richard, Jan. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - London, Jack; Waterhouse, Guy C., Jan. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Manley, Barbara; Welling, Richard; Toksvig, Gudrun; Coleman, George W., Feb. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    Payroll.
  - Reed, Daniel A., Mar. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Tuttle, Edith M.; Bassett, Lucy, Mar. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - McAllister, Peter F.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Snyder, George; Large, Harold; Welling, Richard, Jan. - Feb.1922 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Ferriere, Ad.; Dewey, John, Mar. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Bassett, Lucy, Apr. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    Citizen work cards.
  - Beane, Arthur, Apr. 1922 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    Pay roll.
  - Stone, Kate E., May 1922 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    "Special Constitution of the George Junior Republic"; Pay roll.
  - Welling, Richard; Brunk, Thomas L., Jun. 1022 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    Pay roll. (Annotations.)
  - Welling, Richard; Omessa, Henri; Mayer, Gaston; Lane, Winthrop D.; Miller, Hervey E., Apr. - May1922 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Miller, Hervey E.; Dapping, William O.; Cantor, Eddie; Witmark, Isadore; Welling, Richard; Key, James L., May - Jun.1922 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    George Family genealogy.
  - Passport of William R. George; Letters from citizens. (Annotations.), Jul. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Carballo, Benito, Jul. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - George, Eleanor B.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, Aug. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Letter from William R. George to Esther B. George.; George Junior Republic Scholarships; Letters from citizens. (Annotations.)
  - Letters from William R. George to his family, Aug. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Omessa, Henri, Sept. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Letters from William R. George to his family. (Annotations.)
  - Gammie, John, Sept. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    "Observations" made by William R. George on his European trip; Letters from William R. George to his family.
  - Letters from William R. George to his family, Sept. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Becker, Neal Dow; Welling, Richard; Offer, George E.; Dawson, Charles B., Oct. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Blue, Lou A., Jul. - Aug.1922 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Dawson, Charles B.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Gammie, John; Decker, Neal Dow; Offer, George E., Aug. - Oct.1922 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Stilp, Stephen R.; Kirkland, J.B., Nov. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Bills, Charles B.; Garimaldi, Edward, Nov. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Offer, George E.; Williams, George C., Dec. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    George Junior Republic Lawyers' Association.
  - Bills, Charles B.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Clark, Mary Vida, Dec. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    Bank loan.
  - "The Following for my Children and Grandchildren" by William R. George, 1922 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Freeborn, Edith George, 1922 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    Autobiographical letter from William R. George to his three daughters.
  - "The Junior Republic Idea"; Handwritten draft of William R. George's autobiographical sketch. (Annotations.), 1922 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Eastman, Frank L.; Gillin, J.L.; Welling, Richard; Evans, Eva M.; Novotny, Rudolf, Nov. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    Social Sanitarium.
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher; Miller, Hervey E.; Murray, Homer K., Nov. - Dec.1922 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    Drafts pertaining to principles of junior republics.
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Dawson, Charles B.; Tatnall, Samuel W.; Stoddart, Bessie D., Jan. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    List of possible contributors.
  - Perry, Edward W.; Baldwin, Milton Ford; Dawson, Charles B.; Bruner, Earle D., Jan. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Huntington, Howard; Bruner, Earle D.; LeRoy, Harris G., Feb. 1922 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    George Junior Republic of Western Pennsylvania; George Junior Republic Lawyers' Association.
  - Leighton, Etta V.; McCrea, William A.; Williams, George C.; Saul, Morris B.; Baldwin, Milton F., Jan. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Leighton, Etta V.; Bruner, Earle D.; Callahan, Charles, Feb. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    List of distinguished ex-citizens.
  - Weiss, Hans; Schell, R. Montgomery; Leighton, Etta V., Mar. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Manley, Barbara; Dawson, Charles B.; Berry, Romeyn; Miller, Hervey E., Mar. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Miller, Hervey E., Mar. 1923 (Box 24, Folder 27)